Javier**Porrero**

Full-Stack Javascript Developer

"Creative and highly experienced User Experience Software Developer, able to lead mid-sized teams to perform in an outstanding way.

Proven skills and extensive knowledge in the last usability techniques and trends, guaranteeing a rock-star Application User Experience. Great sense of humor, honest and highly motivated."



in https://ie.linkedin.com/in/jporrero



mail.com



nttps://github.com/JPorry

Work Status -

· U.S Green Card VISA Holder

Professional Skills

0000000000000 ••••••••

Personal Skills

••••••• ••••••• Communication • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • •

Education & Certifications

- · Bsc Computer Science Universidad Politécnica Valencia (2004 - 2010)
- · Android Development Course
- · Advanced Android Apps Course
- · Liferay Themes Development
- · Frontend Development with Backbone
- · M101P: MongoDB for Developers
- · M101JS: MongoDB for Node.js Developers

Experience

Principal Web Developer at Sajan, inc.

May 2014 - Present | Dublin (Ireland)

- · Defining a modern, performant and easy maintainable front end architecture and stack for the new suite of web applications of the Company.
- · Mentoring the front end developers team into good practices, design patterns and new technologies.
- · Coding cross-compatible and multilingual web applications using the latest technologies, with high quality and with a high test coverage, both Unit testing and End to End Testing

Technologies: AngularJS, nodeJS, Express, Grunt, Gulp, SASS, Underscore, Mocha, Protractor

Senior UI Developer at Daon, inc.

October 2013 - May 2014 | Dublin (Ireland)

· Deeply involved in the design and development of web applications for the administration of a suite of products that make use of the Daon's biometrical authentication solution. Focusing on performant and highly secure code to protect sensitive information stored in the cloud.

Technologies: Backbone, Marionette, Handlebars, Grunt, NodeJS, Mocha

Front End Technical Lead at Hewlett-Packard

July 2013 - October 2013 | Dublin (Ireland)

· Working in the complete redesign of the SureSupply product, a web application for controlling the ink levels on your printer that can put you in contact with the best sellers in just one click. Cross-browser development in pure Javascript with an intense use of AJAX and Rest Api communication.

Technologies: Knockout.js, .NET, NodeJS, Apache Cordova, Mocha

UI Developer at Houghton Mifflin Harcourt

March 2013 - July 2013 | Dublin (Ireland)

- · Deeply involved in the design and implementation of a worldwide web-based e-learning solution for kids with ages between 3 and 12 years.
- · Special focus on web tools for collaborative rich text editing, transitions and animations to ensure an astonishing user experience.
- · In charge of ensure the full compatibility with mobile and desktop browsers

Technologies: Backbone, Marionette, Handlebars, Mocha

User Experience Design Team Lead at CSD, s.a.

September 2011 - February 2013 | Valencia (Spain)

- · Successfully managed a team of programmers and designers (six) to provide a seamless User Experience to all of the firm's products: Web (Liferay, HTML5, ...), Mobile (Android) and more.
- · Designed, Architected and built a very sophisticated User Experience for a web accessibility tool for people with disabilities (SaaS), inclusite.com; installed in the most visited online newspaper in Spain (20minutos.com)
- Defined and implemented corporate development processes to integrate UX Design into company Agile practices and projects.
- · Coordinated FrontEnd development for Civil Service using HTML5 + BackBone + Handlebars + Bootstrap.

Technologies: Backbone, Marionette, Handlebars, Bootstrap, Jasmine

Front End Developer at CSD, s.a.

October 2009 - August 2011 | Valencia (Spain)

- · Developed web projects applying the newer UX techniques and mastering HTML5 + CSS3 + Javascript +
- · Built beautiful and efficient web applications for Professional Associations (Architects, Lawyers and Telecommunications) with high amounts of traffic.
- · Developed an awesome web accessibility tool for people with disabilities using Test Driven Development (Jasmine) Object Oriented Javascript, Text-to-Speech and Automatic-Speech-Recognition.

Technologies: Backbone, Marionette, Handlebars, Bootstrap, Jasmine

Web Developer & Designer (Freelancing)

April 2008 - September 2009 | Valencia (Spain)

- · Built website for CINESA Madrid cinema in PHP with ticket selling service.
- · Designed corporate image and entire summer campaign for AZTK Kiteboarding Wear.
- Built an ecommerce for Mobe7 KiteShop using Prestashop integrated with credit card payment and Paypal Integration.

Technologies: Javascript, PHP, Prestashop, ASP

Web Developer at MundoWeb S.L.

April 2006 - March 2008 | Valencia (Spain)

- · Developed web projects for little to medium corporations in PHP + HTML4 + CSS + Javascript.
- · Developed system for Valencia's street lighting warehouse maintenance for ETRALUX, S.A.
- · Built Rich Internet Applications in Flash (Actionscript 3) with an intensive use of multimedia (Audio + Video

Technologies: Actionscript 3, PHP, Javascript, ASP